<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Essays on ★❤★✰ Vicki Boykis ★❤★✰</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/</link><description>Recent content in Essays on ★❤★✰ Vicki Boykis ★❤★✰</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Vicki Boykis.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2021</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2022-01-02-favorite-books/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2022-01-02-favorite-books/</guid><description>This year, just like last year, I got pretty distracted, both with the panedmic, and with work, which I did a ton of technical reading for. As a result, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to nearly as much fiction as I wanted to.. But I still found a few really high-quality reads that I&amp;rsquo;m still thinking about as the new year begins.
Piranesi by Susanna Clarke - I cannot overemphasize how good this book was.</description></item><item><title>Veggie Borscht Recipe</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2021-12-30-borscht/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2021-12-30-borscht/</guid><description>Every week, I make soup for the family and it usually lasts 3-4 days. This week while I was on break, I made borscht and a couple people expressed interest in the recipe, so here it is, as best as I can approximate it.
Most of the Russian recipes I make are very much based on guess work and basically watching my mom make them and then making them over and over again.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2020</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2021-04-16-favorite-books/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2021-04-16-favorite-books/</guid><description>Reading was really hard going in 2020. I was home with two kids of a good chunk of the year and worried that the world was ending the rest of the time. When I did read, I wanted to read things where people who were competent solved problems. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to read about (unattainable) travel or anything that felt like life moving foward, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to read anything about the apocalypse.</description></item><item><title>What we've lost</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2020-12-24-what-weve-lost/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2020-12-24-what-weve-lost/</guid><description>This started as a Twitter thread, but one of my long-time goals has been to not put stuff in Twitter threads, so here it is in longer form. Hopefully this is the start of a nice return to blogging for 2021!
A few days ago, I was putting together our physical photo album for 2020. I do this every year because I&amp;rsquo;m terrified that I&amp;rsquo;m going to lose all of our photos into the digital ether.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2019</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2020-01-01-books/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2020-01-01-books/</guid><description>This year, I knew I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of time. The first half of the year, my pregnancy took a lot of time away from me in the form of body-numbing exhaustion. After working and taking care of my daughter all day, I simply collapsed into bed and fell asleep at 7 at night.
In the second half of the year, my baby was born, thus taking away all of the other time I had.</description></item><item><title>Keeping the world away</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-06-04-kharms-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-06-04-kharms-for-kids/</guid><description>One of the best parts of having a four-year-old is that she&amp;rsquo;s finally old enough to request her own bedtime reading. Usually Mr. B does the bedtime routine and reading, but some nights it&amp;rsquo;s me, and we&amp;rsquo;ll turn on her soft, yellow chicken nightlight, and I&amp;rsquo;ll pull up a chair right next to her bed and read.
She has her own tastes and preferences, and lately, she&amp;rsquo;s been requesting Daniil Kharms&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Everyone runs, flies, and hops&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>The luxury of opting out of digital noise</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-04-25-digital-noise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-04-25-digital-noise/</guid><description>Recently, Ottessa Moshfegh released a new critically-acclaimed novel, &amp;ldquo;My Year of Rest and Relaxation&amp;rdquo;. The story is about a young, thin, and pretty (as she tells us herself many times) Columbia graduate in her mid-20s, in the year 2000. In the midst of a booming and glittering New York City, she&amp;rsquo;s still consumed by the deaths of her hideously neglectful parents, her abusive on-again/off-again boyfriend, and her meaningless job at an art gallery.</description></item><item><title>Meghan Markle's heels</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-03-06-meghan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2019-03-06-meghan/</guid><description>A couple weeks ago, as Mr. B was putting our preschooler to bed, I was lying on the couch, balancing a container of creamy Icelandic yogurt on my lap, and scrolling through People.com. It&amp;rsquo;s something I do a lot these days because I&amp;rsquo;m four and a half months pregnant, and my brain has completely turned to mush.
In order to grow a human being, one of the first things you grow is a placenta, the protective sack of nutritious lifeblood that makes its appearance at the end of a pregnancy as an unimpressive blob.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2018</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-12-27-best-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-12-27-best-books/</guid><description>This year, in reading, I was looking for an escape in great writing. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me whether the writing was fiction or non-fiction, it needed to transport and inspire me. I read nearly 70 books, and for some reason, I had to put down quite a few of them because they weren&amp;rsquo;t getting to the point. Here are my favorites.
Educated by Tara Westover
It seems like everyone&amp;rsquo;s been talking about this book, and for good reason.</description></item><item><title>How the headphone jack-less iPhone came to be</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-11-05-dongles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-11-05-dongles/</guid><description>It so happened that one morning the devil was stuck in an Uber Pool down 101 from the city to Menlo Park (he was late for a meeting with the Facebook content moderation team,) when the driver suddenly took a huge detour and stopped at a leafy driveway in Atherton.
Phil Schiller emerged, wearing a slightly rumpled shirt and holding two iPhones in each hand. Another stuck out haphazardly from his back pocket.</description></item><item><title>America Online and off</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-08-23-america-online-and-off/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-08-23-america-online-and-off/</guid><description>In December of 1777, after weeks of drawn-out fighting near Philadelphia, George Washington and his miserable, cowered soldiers, and their families, came to Valley Forge to nurse their wounds for the winter. The mood could not have been bleaker. Philadelphia was occupied by the British. Less than a quarter of the men had shoes. The rest left bloody footprints in the snow. With their little remaining strength, they built cramped, uninsulated, wooden huts for shelter.</description></item><item><title>Dear Facebook user 752461218193242</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-03-30-dear-facebook-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-03-30-dear-facebook-user/</guid><description>Apologies to Roy Lichtenstein
According to my Facebook data dump, Mark Zuckerberg knows my birthday, all 40 of my interests, my wedding anniversary, and that time in 2011 that I checked in at a castle in Scotland.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Facebook user since it became available to public universities in 2004 - almost fifteen years of my life and countless hours of effort have been put into status boxes, photo updates, and checkins.</description></item><item><title>On competence</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-03-07-on-competence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-03-07-on-competence/</guid><description>Cosette Sweeping, Emile Bayard 1862
I&amp;rsquo;ve watched at least ten different versions of the musical Les Miserables, including the movie and a junior high performance in a middle school in nowhere, Pennsylvania. Ostensibly the songs and roles are always the same, but each production has its own energy, its own highs, and its own flaws.
The best and worst version of Les Mis is &amp;ldquo;Les Miserables in Concert: The 25th Anniversary.</description></item><item><title>It didn't taste like Pamplemousse</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-02-18-pamplemousse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-02-18-pamplemousse/</guid><description>Everyone I know has been talking about LaCroix. The hipster sparkling water has been everywhere lately, from tech startups, to the millennial female-oriented newsletter I subscribe to to pretend I&amp;rsquo;m still in my 20s and see what all the kids are up to these days.
Recently, I decided to try it and see if I could indeed ascend to a higher spiritual plane while drinking it. I went specifically to my local Whole Foods, where they are super-heavy on selling the stuff recently, picked out a six-pack, and brought it home.</description></item><item><title>Strava and the boat in the data lake</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-01-30-strava/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-01-30-strava/</guid><description>Dutch Fishing Boats in a Storm, JMW Turner
Several years ago, I wrote that the Snowden revelations changed the way I understood the internet.
I wrote then, that,
I spend a large majority of my day swimming in the sea of data online. I go to Facebook, Twitter, email, weather, this blog, and everywhere else. In the past, I’ve considered this world mine, safe and managed by me, as long as I was smart and sensible.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2017</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-01-02-favorite-books/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2018-01-02-favorite-books/</guid><description>Every year, it seems like the books I read are completely random. But, what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over time is that I love books that teach me something about the invisible systems that govern how the world works.
My first revelation was many years ago, when I first read Confessions of an Economic Hitman and understood better how international financial systems really work under the covers. Ever since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the look out for both fiction and non-fiction books that peel back the curtain and show the world for what it really is.</description></item><item><title>Logs populi or, Thanks, Netflix!</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-12-14-logs-populi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-12-14-logs-populi/</guid><description>Earlier this week, Netflix tweeted out a seemingly-innocuous throw-away joke about how comforting it is to watch terrible Lifetime-like movies.
The tweet immediately went viral, but not for the reason Netflix probably imagined. In the process of Brand Building, the company ultimately revealed that it was not above exposing proprietary customer viewing data to hundreds of thousands of people on Twitter for quick laughs.
There is a small caveat: having worked previously with streaming viewing data, I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely convinced the data in the tweet was real.</description></item><item><title>The demise of SoundCloud</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-08-11-soundcloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-08-11-soundcloud/</guid><description>They listen to the gramophone, Makovsky
The winter of 2005 was not easy. I was a sophomore in college, taking a heavy courseload, with a scholarship contingent on grades, and finals were right around the corner. I was also working two jobs. It was cold and dark in State College, Pennsylvania. My roommate and I didn&amp;rsquo;t get along - she wrote a public blog post detailing everything that annoyed her about me, including the fact that I was a loud chewer.</description></item><item><title>We know the way</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-06-27-moana/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-06-27-moana/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 10:37 PM on a Wednesday night, and I should be asleep. But I&amp;rsquo;m lying on the edge of my bed at an extremely uncomfortable angle, watching this video with the sound softly turned down so Mr. B, who is downstairs, doesn&amp;rsquo;t hear my secret shame.
(clicky-click on the image)
](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ubZrAmRxy_M)
I cannot express how much joy this video clip, set to this song, brings me. Each time I watch it, I become more hopeful and jubilant about the idea of self-determination, hard work, and human progress.</description></item><item><title>Talk at Skeptech - Manuscripts don't burn</title><link>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-06-19-skeptech/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://veekaybee.github.io/essays/2017-06-19-skeptech/</guid><description>In April, I gave a talk at Skeptech, a fantastic event put together by Mark Hurst to question what the internet&amp;rsquo;s become lately.
The video of the talk is here. My section starts around 1:12:00, but I really encourage you to listen to all of it.
Thank you to WFMU for hosting.
This is the transcript I wrote for my speaker&amp;rsquo;s notes. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t 100% match up with what I talked about, but follows the spirit of the talk.</description></item></channel></rss>